(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.2",
"generated_at": "2026-06-21T23:46:53.893482",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
すてきなホリデイ
[Song: Sutekina Holiday]
近づいている
Approaching is...
冬の足音
...the sound of winter's footsteps.
耳を澄ませば
If you listen closely,
聞こえる鈴の音
you can hear the sound of bells...
寝ぼけた頭に
In my sleepy head,
響く目覚ましを
the ringing alarm...
手さぐりで止めたあと
...after fumbling to turn it off,
雪の気配
there is a sign of snow.
始まりを告げる
Marking the beginning
すてきな季節が
is this wonderful season.
Happy holidays, happy holidays
What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る
Fast asleep,
子供達の手に
in the hands of sleeping children,
抱かれたテディベアも
even the teddy bears being held
もう待ちきれない
can no longer wait.
クリスマスが
Christmas
今年もやって来る
is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を
As if to wipe away
消し去るように
all the sad occurrences.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら
Come now, take off your pajamas,
出かけよう
and let's go outside!
少しずつ白くなる
Let's run through the streets
街路樹を駆け抜けて
as the roadside trees gradually turn white.
華やぎ始めた 街は急ぎ足
The city starting to get lively is in a hurry
贈り物決まる頃 たそがれてく
By the time the presents are decided, twilight falls
かじかんだ指をママが温めるね
Mama warms my frostbitten fingers
Happy holidays,happy holidays What a glorious time of year!
Happy holidays, happy holidays What a glorious time of year!
大切なものはみんなそばにある
The important things are all by my side
穏やかな毎日が続くだく
I want these peaceful days to continue
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas is coming soon
うれしさをかくせない犬や猫まで
Even dogs and cats can't hide their joy
もみの木に灯る明かりをうけて
Receiving the lights that glow on the fir tree
いつもよりやさしそうなパパの目が
Papa's eyes, looking gentler than usual,
笑ってる
are laughing
クリスマスは誰にもやって来る
Christmas comes to everyone
もしひとりぼっちでも寂しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't be lonely
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
Call out to the Santa living in your heart
幼い頃の夢を
The dreams of your childhood...
思い出してごらんよ
...try remembering them
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if to erase the sad things
さあパジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, take off your pajamas and let's go out
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を
Through the roadside trees that are gradually turning white,
駆け抜けて
let's run through
Happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き!雪!本気マジック
Ah, the street looks like a whipped cake, Like! Snow! Really Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
The confetti from the sky is the angel's feathers celebrating the winter festival, Woo
白銀の国へ出かけるの Go Go Go
Heading off to the land of silver, Go Go Go
雪の汽車が街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
Snowy train racing through the city, Choo Choo Choo
絵本みたいな景色を 君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a landscape like a picture book
願い込めて呪文をさあ(さあ) 唱えて(さんはい)
So make a wish and chant the spell (One, two, three!)
ABCDドジシラソラシシマジカルミクルクル Pop!
ABCD Do-si-ra-so-ra-si-si Magical Miru-kuru-kuru Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き!雪!本気 Magic
Ah, the street looks like a whipped cake, Like! Snow! Really Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti from the sky is the angel's feathers celebrating the winter festival
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き!雪!本気 Magic
Light Up, the aurora-colored street is, Like! Snow! Really Magic
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If I could stay a child, Dream Land
Ladies and gentlemen, Welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き Love Love Love
I like this cold season, Love Love Love
アイスも魔法もとけないようにヒューヒューヒュー
So the ice and magic don't melt, Hew Hew Hew
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの? やっぱりドキドキしたいな
Can't we stay like this forever? I want to feel my heart skip a beat
未来求め呪文今(今) 唱えて(さんはい)
For the future, chant the spell now (One, two, three!)
1234水金地火木マジカルミクルクル Pop!
1234, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Magical Miru-kuru-kuru Pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分 好き!雪!本気 Magic
Ah, I feel like a hopping rabbit, Like! Snow! Really Magic
大地がくれる元気得たら 思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
Once you get the energy from the earth, you can live tomorrow just as you wish
まぶしい白に染まるハート 君に
To you, whose heart is dyed in bright white,
好き!雪!本気 Magic
Like! Snow! Really Magic
大人のふりなんていいじゃん
It's okay to pretend to be an adult!
I hear that beat from town
The cute angel will come down
This is my home I'll let you know NAMARA fantastic!
The snowscape is lyrical
The street gonna be magical
I'll set you free in my land oh oh oh
今日の塞ぎも忘れるように（わすれちゃって）
So you can forget today's gloomy feelings (forget about them!)
悩んだって 悩んだって 凍らせて 消せる魔力よ（もっかい）
Even if you worry, worry, it's a magic that freezes it away! (one more time!)
ABCDドシラソファミマジカルミラクルクルPop!
A B C D do-si-la-sol-fa-mi magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town looks like a whipped cake
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Seriously Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
is angel feathers celebrating the winter festival
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気Magic
The lit-up aurora-colored town is Love! Snow! Seriously Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If only I could stay a child in Dream Land
いいじゃん！
That's great!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to be...
らしくいて いいよね？
...myself, is that okay?
弱気で流したジングル
A jingle played with a timid heart
いつもドキドキだね第一声
Always making my heart race, that very first word
（にゃっはろー！）
(Nyahallo!)
震えた声も ノートの文字も
My trembling voice, the words in my notebook
みんなみんな手繋いでGO！
Let's all hold hands and GO!
変わってるねって
"You're a bit strange," they say
（そーなんだ）
(Really?)
なんて言ったの？
What did you say?
（ま、いっか）
(Well, whatever)
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
Even the words I ended up swallowing
君と笑った声でほら咲いて
Look, they bloom with the sound of our laughter
ばんざい！
Hooray!
こんな私でも
Even someone like me...
モーマンタイ！
...is no problem!
好きだって ねぇホント？
Saying "I love you", is it true?
冗談？
A joke?
わかりそう？
Can you tell?
どっち？
Which one?
わかんない！
I don't know!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
受け取って いっせーのーせで！
Receive it! On three... go!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
It'll surely make your heart throb even more
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Stuffed tightly inside the bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to be...
らしくいて いいよね？
...myself, is that okay?
なんて返そうか 没頭！
How should I reply? Immersed!
頭が フットー！
My brain is boiling over!
素真のが もっとー！
Honesty is my motto!
ゲームの中なら Get you!
If it were in a game, I'd get you!
攻略 しょっちゅう？
Always strategizing?
百発 百中！ なののね
A 100% success rate, right?
どったんばったん 踊ったんなら 悩んじゃったって ブギウギ！
If we dance wildly, even if we worry, let's Boogie Woogie!
ハード ずっきゅん ばっきゅん スタートボタン 押せるかな？
Heart-pounding on hard mode, can you press the start button?
ちゃんと言ったっけ？
Did I say it properly?
（どーだっけ？）
(How was it?)
言わなきゃよかった？
Should I not have said it?
（そーだっけ？）
(Was that it?)
抑え込んじゃって また焼きもち
Bottling it up and getting jealous again
あー私なんて しゃがみそうになって防ぐわ
Ah, someone like me feels like crouching down...
これが私だもん
...but this is who I am!
大賛成！
I totally agree!
行くよって ほらこっち！
We're going, look this way!
右曲がっちゃう？
Should we turn right?
左迷っちゃう！
Getting lost on the left!
まっすぐ！
Straight ahead!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
春めいて 舞って 飛び立って！
Spring-like, dancing, flying off!
そっと じっと しゅんとしちゃう日も
Even on days when I feel quiet, still, and down
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
瞳にぱっと映るよ！
It'll flash right in your eyes!
背中を押してメロディー
This melody will push you forward
好きでいていいよね？
It's okay to love you, right?
誰かじゃなくて 君がいいって
It has to be you, no one else
絶対！
Absolutely!
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it as many times as it takes
（もう一回！）
(One more time!)
好きだって ねぇホント？
Saying "I love you", is it true?
冗談？
A joke?
わかりそう？
Can you tell?
どっち？
Which one?
わかんない！
I don't know!
本当だ！
It's true!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
受け取って いっせーのーせで！
Receive it! On three... go!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
It'll surely make your heart throb even more
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Stuffed tightly inside the bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to be...
らしくいて いいよね？
...myself, is that okay?
好きでいて いいよね？
It's okay to love you, right?
はーい！にゃっはろー！
Hi! Nyahallo!
バーチャル巫女アイドル、クリスマス、さくらみこ、新衣装お披露目ライブに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to the new outfit reveal live stream of the virtual Miko idol, Sakura Miko's Christmas stream!
そしてみんな、メリークリスマス！イェーイ！
And everyone, Merry Christmas! Yay!
えー本日、クリスマスはなんと、みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもあります！
Also, today, Christmas, is actually the anniversary of Miko-chan joining Hololive!
おめでとう！ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you, thank you, thank you!
えー、そして！お披露目したこちらの衣装は、200万人記念で作らせていただいた新衣装のルームウェア... ルームウェア衣装となっております！
Also! This outfit we are showing off is the room-wear... room-wear outfit made to celebrate reaching 2 million subscribers!
かわいいでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
あのね、まあいつも新衣装で悩んでるんですけど
You see, I always struggle with deciding on new outfits, but...
作りたいなってずっと思ってたんだけど、なかなかね
I had always wanted to make this, but I couldn't really...
踏み切れなかった
...take the plunge.
このルームウェアをね、200万人記念で作らせてもらいました。
So, I was allowed to make this room wear to celebrate reaching 2 million subscribers!
いいアイデアだよね、これね？
It's a great idea, right?
そして、ちょっと見ていただくんですけど、こちら、じゃじゃーん！
And, please take a look at this, ta-da!
ヘアバンド！
A hairband!
Mikopiのヘアバンドになってます。
It's a Mikopi-themed hairband.
ちょっとふわふわしてる、かわいいし、
It's fluffy and cute!
ま、このピンもいっぱい付いてて、イヤリングもかわいくって、
And it has lots of pins on it, and the earrings are super cute too,
あとこの、サクランボになってるんですよ、めっちゃネックレス。かわいい！
and this necklace is shaped like cherries. So cute!
で、このね、だぼっとした、ニットに、
And this baggy knit cardigan...
もうちょっとセクシーなね、ちょっとセクシーな、
...with somewhat sexy, a bit sexy...
ルームウェアとなってます。あの、ちょっとね、
...room wear. You see, normally...
みこちゃん、おへそ見せないんですけど、
Miko-chan doesn't show her belly button, but...
おへそが、見えます！
now you can see my belly button!
ちょっと、あの、若干、
It's, well, a little bit...
寒くなるとね、食べたくなって若干ぷにってる気もしなくもないけど、
When it gets cold, I want to eat, so it might be a bit pudgy, but...
まあ、まあ、まあ、気にしたら負けですからね。
well, if you worry about it, you lose!
大丈夫、健康的な範囲だからね、大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's fine, it's within a healthy range, so it's totally fine!
ということで、あのね、隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですけど、
So, I'd like you to check out every little detail, but...
もっとね、見ていただきたいところがあります。
there's something else I really want you to see.
見て！この、お部屋！かわいい！
Look at this room! It's so cute!
今日のライブはなんと、トナリコさんにね、制作をお願いいたしまして、作ってます！
For today's live, we actually had Toribal Co. create this room!
本当にどうもありがとうございます。めっちゃかわいいの！
Thank you so much! It's super cute!
もう本当にね、35Pとかね、このソファとかね、
They made Mikopi and this sofa,
もうめちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいております。この後もね、ちょっとね、
and everything in such amazing detail. Later on, there will also be...
びっくりするギミックとかもありますので、お楽しみに！
...some surprising gimmicks, so look forward to them!
じゃあね、あ、そうだ、ハッシュタグだ、ハッシュタグ。
Now, oh, right! The hashtag, the hashtag!
ハッシュタグは、こちら！あの、さくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね、
The hashtag is this one: #さくらみこ新衣装XmasLIVE!
応援してください。スクショもたくさん撮ってね。
Please cheer me on with it. Also, take lots of screenshots!
ちょっとスクショタイム。はい！
Time for a quick screenshot session! Here we go!
てれん！
Tada!
あ、かわいい！あ、かわいい！
Ah, cute! So cute!
あ、かわいい！かわいい！あ、かわいい！
Oh, cute! Cute! So cute!
はい、かわいい！はい、かわいい！
Yep, cute! Indeed, cute!
はい、かわいい！
So cute!
Super cute!
ということでね、みんなたくさん撮ったよね？
Alright, you all got plenty of shots, right?
はい、お願いしまーす！
Yes! Please share them!
そして、なんと最後に重大告知もありますので、 wagon_icon
And also, we have a major announcement at the very end,
最後までぜひ、お見逃しなく！ありがとう！
so make sure to watch until the end! Thank you!
よろしくね！
Stay tuned!
それでは、次の曲行きますか！
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
こちらにね、移動させていただきまして、
Let me just move over here...
はい！
Okay!
それでは、次の曲、行くぞー！
Alright, here we go with the next song!
半端ないぱっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（はい）
So crazy, pappa-pappa-pappa (Yeah!)
限界突破ぱっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（はい）
Breaking limits, pappa-pappa-pappa (Yeah!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（はい）
Every day is so crazy, pappa-pappa-pappa (Yeah!)
限界突破ぱっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（はい）
Breaking limits, pappa-pappa-pappa (Yeah!)
明日の私に幸あれ
May tomorrow bring me happiness!
最低温度 uh遮るゴースト
The lowest temperature, uh, a blocking ghost
八百万の嫌な外の要素
Eight million annoying external factors
「何の気ない」と超あっけらかんと
With a completely casual, carefree look,
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
say bye-bye to someone getting in the way without any malice!
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing my personal slacking time, protecting 5 PM to 9 AM is a must!
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
And also not forgetting love, romance, and sweet treats...
とどのつまり
To sum it up...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
Overwork is strictly off-limits, I'm issuing a warning here!
ねえ楽して苦なくして生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living easily without any struggles is so hard, isn't it?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある保存
Because in sweet honey like 'stability', 'cheats', and 'cramming', there's always a trap!
やっ！
Yah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when you get sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play because you want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when you get hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when you are happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
And if you are sad, it's fine to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of my tomorrow, I'll somehow do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Doing my best today so I don't have to do my best tomorrow!
退屈じゃないやこれ多分そう
It's not boring, I think that's probably right
だなんやでやることやっています！
I'm somehow getting things done anyway!
WHAT? AND BUT
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
It doesn't matter if nobody knows!
私には私のマイルール
I've got my own personal rules
明日ラクするためにはハイチーズ
Say 'Cheese!' to make tomorrow easier
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きたいのです
Surprisingly, I just want to live each day with love and peace like this!
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy
ドドキドキしときたい
I want to feel my heart pounding
Let Let Let me shine
明日天気になれ
Hope it's sunny tomorrow!
To To To be excite
To, to, to be excited
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance even more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday
木金土日月
Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday!
辛くなったら歌う
Sing when it gets tough
むかついたら愚痴る
Grumble when you get annoyed
やりたいようにやる
Just do whatever you want
それができたら苦労しないわ
But it wouldn't be a struggle if I could do that!
常に一喜一憂
Constantly swinging between joy and sorrow
適度にセーブ リスクは回避しつつで まあ頑張るのさ
I'll save moderately, avoiding risks, and somehow keep working hard.
適当にとまでは言うまいが まあ頑張るのさ
I won't go so far as to say 'half-heartedly', but I'll do my best.
夢の中では…
In my dreams...
ずっとぐうたらしてやるんだ
I'll just laze around forever.
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく 明日の私のため
Not for someone else's sake, but for my future self!
楽するために 苦しいことも 乗り越えちゃうんだからね
To make things easier, I'll even overcome the painful things!
やりたくないこと やらないために やりたくないことやれ
To avoid doing what I don't want to do, I have to do what I don't want to do!
あれ？これって結果頑張れてる？
Huh? Does this mean I'm actually working hard?
私とってもえらいじゃないか
Aren't I just super admirable?
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時-9時は死守マスト
Securing my own lazy time; defending 5 PM to 9 AM is an absolute must!
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに とどのつまり
Furthermore, not forgetting love, romance, and sweets; in the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm even putting up warnings that overworking is strictly prohibited!
ねえ楽して苦なくして生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living easily without any suffering is pretty difficult, huh?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある やっ！
Because with 'stability', 'cheats', and 'cramming', sweet honey always has a trap. Yah!
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I get hungry, I eat food.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために 今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of my future self, I'll somehow get through today too.
明日も頑張らなくていいように 頑張るのさ
I'll work hard today, so that I won't have to work hard tomorrow.
半端ないぱっぱらぱっぱっぱっ
Unbelievable pa-para-pa-pa-pa!
限界突破らぱっぱっぱっ
Breaking limits pa-para-pa-pa-pa!
毎日半端ないぱっぱらぱっぱっ
Every day is unbelievable pa-para-pa-pa-pa!
限界突破らぱっぱらぱっぱらぱっぱら
Breaking limits pa-para-pa-para-pa-para-pa-pa!
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとりエックスエックスしてるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're doing 'XX' all by yourself.
ピクンピクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Trembling and twitching, your voice is leaking completely.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ 効いてんの？
Just say it honestly, it's already been exposed, so just say it. Is it working?
普通普通恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ
Is it normal, normally embarrassing? Everyone is just hiding it.
モニタリング
Monitoring
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing your complaints away in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
We're in this together until morning. Even if you cry more, I'll catch you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
Mwah! お願い きみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 涸れてしまう 濡れていたい
If you don't cry, I'll dry up. I want to be wet.
ねえ いいでしょう？ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
Mwah! お願い きみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Lean on me completely, a sick love is just the best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ 君の“痛い”感じていたい
If you don't share it, I want to feel your 'pain'.
ねえ いいでしょう？ 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
見たい...
I want to see...
見たいの きみの中
I want to see inside of you.
見たい...
I want to see...
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're feeling frustrated all by yourself.
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん きみを推すことをやめない
My heart is throbbing and racing, I'll never stop supporting you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're a capable person.
つらい時は弱いくらいで丁度いい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When times are tough, being a bit weak is just right. I still love you regardless.
Mwah! お願い きみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
名前を呼んでよ いつだって会いに参上
Call my name, I'll always show up to see you.
きみはひとりだ だから歌う「ひとりじゃない」
You are alone, so I sing 'you are not alone'.
もういいでしょう ソロプレイはお仕舞いなんだってば
That's enough, isn't it? I'm telling you, solo play is over.
きみが病めるときも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you are sick, I will be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I will always watch over you. Yes, there's nothing to fear.
Mwah! お願いきみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 涸れてしまう 濡れていたい
If you don't cry, I'll dry up. I want to be wet.
ねえ いいでしょう？ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
Mwah! お願いきみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Lean on me completely, a sick love is just the best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ 君の“痛い”感じていたい 覗いていたい
If you don't share it, I want to feel your 'pain', I want to peek inside.
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing your complaints away in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
We're in this together until morning. Even if you cry more, I'll catch you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないで 出してってば さあ
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, come on.
ずうっといっしょ！
Together forever!
充電器を貸して！
Lend me a charger!
またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
Because of you again, I'm worn down.
終電見逃して
I missed the last train...
またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
...and because of me again, you couldn't go home.
繋がっていようね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging each other into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル
Our youth, where we dragged each other down...
沈殿した思い出ずっといっしょ！
...with our settled memories, we're together forever!
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on parent-teacher day, I felt like nobody was watching me.
散々死に切って 昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Dying over and over, I tried not to expect anything from the daytime city.
そうやって守った孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected like that was completely messed up.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly,
こんな顔だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I can't bring myself to cherish a face like this anyway.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together...
ささやかな幸せが
...our small happiness...
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
...I hope they've become an irreplaceable trauma for you.
はなればなれなんて誰かが吐かせたバグだよね？
Being apart is just a bug someone spat out, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live out my days as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is precious to you?
A. 今、失くしたそれ
A. That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've gone and made a mistake with me,
取り返しがつかないね
there's no taking it back.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中で
within our gruesome history,
ずっといっしょ！
together forever!
もうちょっとふつうに
I wanted to feel sad about sad things,
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
a bit more normally.
長調のチューンに
To a major-key tune,
感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to consign my feelings and find relief.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please live as hard as you can, at the very least."
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly,
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the beck and call of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで
Only you, all alone,
あたしの目、瞑んで
closing my eyes,
幸せになろうなんて思わないで防いで
don't you dare think you can be happy.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
Since the night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I've been broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live out my days as your lifelong regret,
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
like a ring that can no longer be taken off.
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている 最低だよ
It flashes back over and over again, it's the absolute worst.
一緒に居た時のほうが あたし可愛かったなあ
The me back when we were together was much cuter.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live out my days as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is precious to you?
A. 今、失くしたそれ
A. That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've gone and made a mistake with me,
取り返しがつかないね防いで
there's no taking it back.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと眠っていても
even if you're sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢で ずっといっしょ！
with matching nightmares, together forever!
天天地獄国
Tenten Tengoku Jigokukoku
天、天、天、天、天...
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven...
天天地獄国
Tenten Tengoku Jigokukoku!
Open Sesame
闇と光の交わる fanatic_
A fanatic crossing of darkness and light,
今宵味わう psychedelic_
tonight I taste psychedelic.
踊り絡まりあう zodiac_
Dancing and entangling, zodiac,
恋の駆け引きの tie-break_
tie-break of love's pull and push.
飾らない存在 ただ気を惹きたい_
An unadorned presence, I just want to attract attention,
夢見心地 触れ合い 惑わせたい_
dreamlike, touching, I want to mesmerize you.
曖昧 溶けない cocktailは甘い_
An ambiguous, undissolving cocktail is sweet,_
鮮やかな赤いeye 見つめて限界_
staring into vibrant red eyes, reaching my limit.
月夜に誘われ 天使と悪魔と_
Invited by the moonlit night, angels and demons...
天使と悪魔と天使と悪魔が_
...angels and demons, angels and demons...
偶さか接した 天国地獄の_
...happened to contact, heaven and hell's...
天国地獄の 天国地獄の_
...heaven and hell's, heaven and hell's..._
狭間で出会った 天使と悪魔と_
...meeting in the gap, angels and demons...
天使と悪魔と天使と悪魔が_
...angels and demons, angels and demons...
集って踊れば 天国地獄の_
...gathering and dancing, heaven and hell's...
天国地獄の 天国地獄の_
...heaven and hell's, heaven and hell's...
門が開く_
...gates open!
闇と光の交わる fanatic_
A fanatic crossing of darkness and light,
今宵味わう psychedelic_
tonight I taste psychedelic.
踊り絡まりあう zodiac_
Dancing and entangling, zodiac,
恋の駆け引きの tie-break_
tie-break of love's pull and push.
Dead Alive Dead Alive_
Death Death Death_
Birth Birth Birth_
Dead Alive Dead Alive_
Death Birth Death Birth Death_
Let's go!_
生きた魂を trayに置いて_
Place the living souls on the tray,
めくる5枚の card 揺れる炎_
flip the five cards, the flickering flames.
先にあなたが raiseしたなら_
If you raise first,
もう迷わない glass飲み干して_
I won't hesitate anymore, drain the glass.
今夜 All-in 降りない この勝負_
Tonight All-in, no folding in this game.
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いてゆく。_
Now, the gates connecting heaven and hell are opening.
天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い..._
Angels and demons, the dead and the living mingle, dancing and laughing...
すべては混沌の中に飲み込まれてゆく
Everything is swallowed into chaos.
それは世界の終焉であり
It is the end of the world,
新たなる始まりでもあるのだった
and it was also a new beginning.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Birth Birth Death Birth Death Birth!
天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
月夜に誘われ
Enticed by the moonlit night,
天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
たまたま接した
happened to come into contact.
天国 地獄の 恍惚消えない 果てない moon-night
The ecstasy of heaven and hell won't fade, in this endless moonlit night.
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Of heaven and hell, of heaven and hell,
狭間で出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in the crevice, angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
gathering to dance in heaven and hell, heaven and hell, heaven and hell...
狭間で出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in the crevice, angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば dance dance dance dance
gathering to dance, dance, dance, dance!
天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
clumsy trick
[Song: clumsy trick]
回想中熱くなりお茶いかが？
While reminiscing, I get hot under the collar. How about some tea?
冷静に大人で
Act calm and mature.
ハートは君にまだ教えずに
Without revealing my heart to you yet,
ご相談チラチラと
I glance over, seeking advice.
余裕 身に着けて言う「お相手はYou?」
With an air of composure, I ask, "Is my partner you?"
ドラマのようなことしない女優
An actress who doesn't do dramatic things.
噛めば噛むほど美味しい
The more you chew, the more delicious...
Lady 例に甘え方を見せてほしい
Lady, for example, I want you to show me how you pamper.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break out, but, mm, I can't change.
自由型のいい子は好き放題
A freestyle good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅 も～わからないの
I don't even know the right balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦ってる
Just pretending to be gentle while feeling rushed.
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し
My demands are casual, dodging the topic,
嬉しさを誤魔化し
covering up my joy.
反省会駆け引きを学びたい
I want to learn tactics in our post-mortem meeting,
裏技をつらつらと
listing out secret techniques.
至急きっかけのキュー！慌ててもCute
Urgent! Give me the cue! Even in a panic, it's cute.
そんな事なんて仕立てないIQ
I don't have the IQ to set something like that up.
あの手この手も出来ない
I can't even pull off this trick or that,
Lady 例におとし まとめてほしい
Lady, for example, I want you to settle things for me.
遠慮して ん～はしゃげないの
Holding back, mm, I can't let loose.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead you perfectly, but...
そのボーダー も～超えらんないの
I just can't cross that border anymore.
そもそもものの話まだ隠してる
I'm still hiding the core of the story.
（読めない読めない）
(Unreadable, unreadable)
恋は
Love is...
（読めない読めない）
(Unreadable, unreadable)
そっと口角上げ君を...魅せ君を
Gently raising the corners of my mouth... to charm you,
（包み包み）
(wrapping, wrapping)
そっと心タップ君を...あぁ君を
Gently tapping your heart... ah, you,
（包み包み）
(wrapping, wrapping)
知りたい
I want to know.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break out, but, mm, I can't change.
自由型のいい子は好き放題
A freestyle good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅 も～わからないの
I don't even know the right balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦ってもっと
Just pretending to be gentle while feeling rushed, even more.
ん～はしゃげないの
Mm, I can't let loose!
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead everything well, but
そのボーダーも～超えらんないの
I can't even cross that border
そもそもの話まだ隠して
I'm still hiding the story in the first place
見つめてる
And watching you
Snow halation
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, the current feeling
空から降ってきたみたい
Seems like it came falling from the sky
特別な季節の色が
The special colors of the season
ときめきを見せるよ
show excitement
初めて出会った時から
Since the first time we met
予感に騒ぐ 心のMelody
The melody of our excited hearts
とめられない とまらない なぜ
Unstoppable, won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Reach out! To this painful sadness...
名前をつけようか "Snow halation"
...let's give it the name "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに
Don't wait until our feelings overlap
悔しいけど 好きって純情
It's frustrating, but it's pure love to love you
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
In the midst of hesitation, you can't hold back
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Approve the courage to jump in, the start is near!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without a sound, without a sign
静かに運命は変わる
Our destiny quietly changes
これからの未来に 胸の
Towards the future ahead,
鼓動が早くなる
the beating of my chest quickens
たとえば 困ったときには
For example, when you're in trouble,
すぐ駆けつけて 抱きしめたくて
I want to rush to you and hold you tight
どこにいても どこでも Fly high
No matter where you are, fly high!
急いで いつのまにか
Hastily, before we knew it,
大きくなりすぎた "True emotion"
our "True emotion" has grown too big
夢だけみてる様じゃつらいよ
It's painful to only look at dreams
恋人は君って言いたい
I want to tell you that you're my love
優しい目が とまどってる イヤだよ
Your gentle eyes look confused, and I hate it
このまま一気に 愛情 あずけて Please!!
Please let me entrust my love to you all at once!
届けて 切なさには
Reach out! To this painful sadness...
名前をつけようか "Snow halation"
...let's give it the name "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに
Don't wait until our feelings overlap
悔しいけど 好きって純情
It's frustrating, but it's pure love to love you
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
In the midst of hesitation, you can't hold back
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Approve the courage to jump in, the start is near!
はーい！
Hi!
みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Is everyone having fun?
ゲストもね、たくさん来て下さいました。みんなありがとう！
We also had so many guests come. Thank you, everyone!
そして、見てください！
And, look!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるっと回転して
The stage spun around a bit...
外にやってきました！凄くないですか？
and we came outside! Isn't it amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、綺麗でね。
The illuminations are beautiful, too.
クリスマスって感じで、ちょっと…もうちょっと若干肌寒いレベルですけどね。
It really feels like Christmas... although it's actually slightly chilly.
もう凄い綺麗だよね、見て。凄い。
It's really beautiful, look. Amazing.
凄い！
Amazing!
わー
Wow...
はい。
Yes.
どうもありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
そして、なんと次で最後の曲になるんですが…
And actually, the next one is the last song...
なんと次の曲は、新曲です！わー！
But amazingly, the next song is a brand new song! Yay!
みこちゃん、ファーストアルバム以来のね、ソロの新曲となります！
It's Miko's first solo new song since her first album!
ソロライブを経て、みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております。
Having completed her solo live, this is a song where Miko takes another new step forward.
それでは、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
咲き誇れアイドル
Bloom Gloriously, Idol.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad that I'm clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom gloriously.
初のイベント 需要無しデフォ
My first event, the default is no demand.
そんな私が夢を見ました保存
That kind of me had a dream.
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called an idol,
憧れて
longing for it.
「無敵エリート」「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible elite," "smiling is a cheat."
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who watch over this kind of me,
好きなとこはどこですか？
What is it you like about me?
わがままを許して
Forgive my selfishness.
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで保存
My stage experience points are soaked in tears,
それでも絶対負けたくない
But even so, I absolutely don't want to lose.
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
I'll put a message on the cherry blossoms and send it to you,
愛で溢れますように
So that it overflows with love.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad that I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom gloriously,
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end with just delusions.
私らしく桜色 ね
I'm being myself, cherry blossom colored, okay?
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Polished skills, demonstrating my real ability,
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy have also increased,
アイドルとして生きてる
I'm living as an idol,
君のおかげ
It's all thanks to you.
アホ毛はキュート！勝ち確ルート！
My ahoge is cute! A guaranteed victory route!
そんな私についてきてよね！保存
Follow me, will you!
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy parts are forgiven,
最強じゃん！
Isn't it the strongest!?
痛いの言いたいの グッと飲み込んで
I swallow the pain I want to speak of,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with smiles,
桜前線が君の町に
So that the cherry blossom front
春を届けるように
Delivers spring to your town.
アイドルだけは
Idol is the only thing
譲りたくないんだ
I don't want to yield.
君に魅せたいんだ
I want to charm you,
理想へ挑むよ
I'm challenging the ideal,
駆け抜けろ
run through it.
最高景色見せてあげる保存
I'll show you the highest view,
信じていいよ 桜を
You can believe in the cherry blossoms,
さぁ
Come on,
皆で咲かそう保存
Let's all make them bloom,
満開のピンクで世界染めて
Dye the world in full-bloom pink.
あぁ
Ah,
この涙はね
this tear,
悲しい方じゃないから
it's not because I'm sad,
安心して
so rest assured.
きれいだね
(It's beautiful.)
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad that I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom gloriously,
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end with just delusions.
私らしく桜色 ね
I'm being myself, cherry blossom colored, okay?
咲き誇れアイドル
[Song: Sakihokore Idol]
みんなー！みこの新衣装クリスマス、新衣装お披露目ライブを見てくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for watching Miko's New Outfit Christmas, New Outfit Reveal Live!
ここで、告知が３つあります！まずは、こちら！
Here, I have three announcements! First is this one!
200万人記念、ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
To commemorate reaching 2 million subscribers, Roomwear Outfit Reveal Commemorative Goods will be on sale!
キービジュアルは、おるだん先生に描いてもらいました！いつもありがとうございます！
The key visual was drawn by Orudan-sensei! Thank you as always!
イラストのテーマは、お部屋でのんびりしているみこです！
The theme of the illustration is Miko relaxing in her room!
それでは、１つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！リバーシブルブランケット！
First is this one! Reversible Blanket!
表には35P、裏にはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります！
On the front is 35P, and on the back is a large illustration of Miko!
丸く包むと、みんなも35Pのぬいぐるみになっちゃうよ！
If you wrap it up round, you can become a 35P plushie too!
続いて、みことおそろい35Pヘアバンド！
Next is Miko's matching 35P Hairband!
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです！
It's a hairband matching Miko's new outfit!
毎日使いができるアイテムです！使ってね！
It's an item you can use every day! Please use it!
次は、みこの愛用35Pマグカップです！
Next is Miko's favorite 35P Mug!
お耳も付いてるマグカップなんだよ！忠実に再現できました！
It's a mug with ears! It was faithfully recreated!
飲み物を入れてもよし、小物入れにするもよし！
You can put drinks in it, or use it as a small item container!
素敵なおうちタイムのお供に使ってね！
Please use it to accompany your wonderful time at home!
最後は、ルームウェアみこの35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみです！
Lastly, Roomwear Miko's 35P Hugging Sleeping Plushie!
ルームウェア衣装のみこが、ぬいぐるみになりました！
Miko in her roomwear outfit has become a plushie!
みんなも一緒におやすみしようね！
Everyone, let's go to sleep together!
フルセットはこんな感じです！
This is what the full set looks like!
そして、そして！フルセット購入特典は、ポストカードです！
And also! The full set purchase bonus is a postcard!
今回は、箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ入りになっております！
This time, it comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature and message!
みんな、ぜひぜひ購入してくださいね！
Everyone, please be sure to buy it!
告知、２つ目は、こちら！
The second announcement is this!
本日初披露した新曲「咲き誇れアイドル」が、本日0時から配信開始！
The new song 'Sakihokore Idol' performed for the first time today starts streaming today at midnight!
ファーストソロライブを終えて、次のステージに向かっていく気持ちをHoneyWorksさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
HoneyWorks wrote this song about the feelings of moving on to the next stage after completing the first solo live!
そして、そして！このあと、「咲き誇れアイドル」のMVがプレミア公開となります！
And also! The music video for 'Sakihokore Idol' will have its premiere after this!
とっても可愛いので、みんなたくさん聴いて観てくださいね！
It's super cute, so everyone please listen and watch it a lot!
告知、３つ目は、こちら！
The third announcement is this!
なんと！さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗のコラボが2026年も決定しました！
To our surprise! The Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collaboration has been confirmed for 2026 as well!
なんと、４回目ですよ！
Wow, it's the fourth time!
今回の開催期間は、2026年2月20日から3月31日までです！
This time, the period will be from February 20th to March 31st, 2026!
やったー！本当にね、こんなに長く続いているのはみんなのおかげでもありますし、
Hooray! Honestly, that we've been able to continue this long is all thanks to everyone,
鳴門鯛焼本舗さん、本当にありがとうございます！
And Naruto Taiyaki Honpo, thank you so much!
詳細情報は、追ってみこのXなどで告知するので、楽しみにしていてくださいね！
Detailed information will be announced on Miko's X later, so please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう、みんな！メリークリスマス！
Thank you so much for today, everyone! Merry Christmas!
おつみこでした！バイバーイ！
Otsumiko! Bye-bye!